说真的  肯定发生了什么事
I'm telling you, something happened,
我们起了变化
something changed.
最近我们之间一直怪怪的
It's been weird between us lately.
只是最近吗
Lately?
凯特  你们俩都怪了四年了
Kate, it's been weird for four years.
不  这次不一样
No, this is different.
他变了  好像在疏远我
He's different. It's like he's pulling away.
你也不能怪他啊
Well, can you blame him?
没准儿只是等累了
He's probably tired of waiting.
等啥啊
Waiting for what?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
他为你痴狂
The guy is crazy about you.
不管你怎么掩饰  你也迷恋着他
And despite your little act, you're crazy about him.
怎么  这难不成还是惊天大秘密啊
Oh, what, was that supposed to be some big secret?
必须的
Yes.
好吧
No.
你觉得他知道吗
Do you think he knows?
记得他以前什么样儿吗
You remember how he used to be,
左拥右抱的
girl on either arm?
现在是不是看不见他那样儿了
You really don't see that guy too much anymore.
你觉得是啥原因呢
Why do you think that is?
他在等你
He's waiting for you.
我知道  但是  蕾妮
Yeah, but, Lanie--
我知道  你有心结没解开
I know. You're dealing with stuff.
但你不让他等你一辈子啊
But you cannot ask him to wait forever.
当然了  除非你不在意他疏远你
Unless, of course, you're okay with him pulling away.
要是我们俩不合拍
What if it doesn't work?
像你和哈维一样分开了呢
What if it ends up like you and Javi?
起码我们尝试过了
Well, at least we gave it a shot.
我们俩分手了  那又怎么样
And so it didn't work out. So what?
我们现在都开始新生活了
Now we can move on,
除了有时候滚滚床单
give or take the occasional booty call.
我只是  不想失去现在拥有的一切
I just--I don't want to lose what we have, you know?
得了吧  傻姑娘
Girl, please.
你们现在有啥啊
What exactly do you have, really?
友谊啊
A friendship.
错  你我之间是友谊
No. What you and I have is a friendship.
你和卡塞尔处于停滞不前
What you and Castle have is a holding pattern.
激情消退之前你们还能坚持多久
How long can you circle before the fuel runs out?
别以为这事儿就完了  凯特·贝克特
Don't think you were saved by the bell, Kate Beckett.
作为朋友我不是会袖手旁观的
As your friend, I'm not gonna let this drop.
那怎么办  向他坦白吗
So what, you think I should tell him how I feel?
对
Yes.
你天天追捕杀人犯  这也不在话下
You hunt murderers for a living. You can do this.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
我只是想找个恰当的时间
I just--I-I have to find the right time.
现在就是最佳时机
No time like the present.
搞你妹...
What the...
转念一想
On second thought,
也许你该再等等
maybe you should wait a bit.
听到了吗  莱恩叫我呢  先走了
What's that? Ryan's calling. I gotta go.
我一小时以后再打给你
I'll call you in about an hour.
哈喽啊
Hey there.
我感觉像在看一集烂透了的《迈阿密风云》
I feel like I just walked into a bad episode of "Miami Vice."
首先《迈阿密风云》集集精彩
Okay, first, there are no bad episodes of "Miami Vice."
其次  被害人是谁
Second, who died?
你  瞧你的脸色吧
You from the looks of it.
像被大卡车碾过一样
You look like you just got run over by a truck.
是啊  奇遇大卡车
Yeah, a truck delivering a shipment of awesome.
我就是飞去维加斯度了个周末
No, I just flew into Vegas for the weekend.
想换点儿景色看看
Just needed a little change of scenery.
然后在高筹码扑克桌上赢了个金发美女吗
And you won the blonde in a high-stakes poker match?
没有  回程的飞机上遇到的
No, I met her on the flight back.
那你就把车交给她了
And you just gave her your car?
贾辛达恰好是个值得信赖的人
Jacinda happens to be a very trustworthy person.
她是头等舱的空姐
She's a first-class flight attendant.
我又不是把社会保险号给了她
It's not like I gave her my social security number.
卡塞尔
Castle...
你还好吗
Is everything okay?
再好不过了
Never better.
被害人叫娜奥米·艾伦  25岁
Our victim's Naomi Allen, age 25.
绿卡显示她是英国国民
Her green card indicates that she's a British national.
莱恩已经通知了领事馆
Ryan is notifying the consulate.
她的地址写得是苏豪区
Her address is in SoHo.
大老远的跑这里来干吗呢
What was she doing all the way down here?
谁知道呢  但是她是在遇害前两小时入住的
Don't know, but she checked in two hours before she was killed.
希望他们AA制付的房钱
I hope they prorated the room.
好消息是我们有位目击证人
Good news is, we have a witness.
发现尸体的女仆看到一个男人逃走了
The maid who discovered the body saw a guy run out.
她看清楚脸了吗
Did the maid get a good look?
她和画师在一起
She's with the sketch artist now.
不管这个人是谁  他都在找什么东西
Well, whoever he is, he was looking for something.
这个房间被搜过
This place has been searched.
不过我们知道她并没遭劫
The one thing we do know is that she was not robbed.
钱包  手表和现金都在
Her wallet, watch, and cash were untouched.
蕾妮  什么情况
Hey, Lanie, how does it look?
你等得太久了
Like you waited too long.
我问被害人
The vic.
她是被掐死的  但是也挣扎过
She was strangled but she went down with a fight.
初步看她跟凶手打过一架
Prelim suggests a sign of a struggle.
脸上吃了一拳
She took one to the face.
穿着时尚  充满魅力的女人
A well-dressed, attractive woman
却来破烂的汽车旅馆
in a seedy motel
又有个男人逃离犯罪现场
and a guy who flees the crime scene--
看来是一夜情出了差错
This might have been a one-night stand gone wrong.
现在是在说被害人还是卡塞尔
Are we talking about the victim or Castle?
埃斯波
Hey, Espo.
说
Yeah.
你能不能联系一下她的亲属
Can you contact the next of kin
画像完成后再排查一下附近区域
and canvass the area once the sketch is done?
好
Yeah, no problem.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
在手包的侧袋里发现了她的名片
Found the vic's business card in the side pocket of her purse.
看来她在曼哈顿工作
Looks like she works in Manhattan.
"姬曼集团  娜奥米·艾伦"
"Naomi Allen, Kittman Group."
是的  我是她在美国的经纪人
Yes, I was her U.S. booking agent.
娜奥米是我们最棒的模特之一
Naomi was one of our top models.
所以她来纽约是为了工作吗
So she was in the city for work?
她往返于纽约和伦敦
She split her time between here and London.
顶尖模特一般
The good ones usually end up
会在纽约待上大半年时间
spending at least half the year in New York.
你知不知道为什么
Now do you have any idea
她昨晚会去亚力山卓汽车旅馆
why she was at the Alexandria Motel last night?
不知道  我从来没听说过那个地方
Uh, no. I've never even heard of it.
是个时租旅馆
It's one of those, um, pay-by-the-hour places.
你认识这个人吗
Do you recognize this man?
不  不认识
No. No, I don't.
但你知道他可能是谁吧
But you do have an idea of who he might be.
事实上...
It's just...
最近
lately,
娜奥米做了改变
Naomi was making some choices.
什么样的改变
What kind of choices?
她似乎厌倦了正常的模特工作
Well, she seemed to have lost interest in standard modeling jobs.
最近  她接了很多
Recently, she had been booking more, uh,
非常规的活儿
unconventional gigs.
比如说
Like what?
我听说一个月前伦敦办事处
Well, I heard the London office booked her to attend
预约她去参加国外高官的生日派对
the birthday party of some foreign dignitary a few months ago.
她被雇佣去参加派对
She was hired to go to a party?
模特被雇佣去参加高端的活动很正常
It's common for models to get hired to pretty-up an event.
一些姑娘们靠这个赚一些零花钱
Some girls do it to pick up extra cash.
其他的把它当做和富人们联络的机会
And other girls do it as a way of connecting with wealthy men.
等等  你是说
Uh, wait. Are you saying
娜奥米出租自己当应召女郎
that Naomi was hiring herself out as an escort?
我就是没想到娜奥米这样的好姑娘
You just don't see girls as good as Naomi
干这些派对的活
taking these party jobs.
除非这里面包含了更大的收入
Not unless there's a bigger payout involved somewhere.
她最近参加这样的活动了吗
Do you know if she took on any of these kinds of gigs recently?
那不是我们的主业
It's not really what we do.
不过她的确想让我帮她参加昨晚的一个活动
She did want me to try to get her into an event last night, though,
是在市中心举行的一个专辑发布会
uh, an album launch party in midtown.
但是我没有什么关系
But I didn't have any connections to it.
昨天晚上
Last night?
是的
Yeah.
你跟我想的一样吗
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
是啊  我们应该举办一个派对
Yeah, that we should throw a party
再雇一群模特
and hire a bunch of models.
不
No.
娜奥米昨晚可能混进了那个派对
That maybe Naomi somehow got into that party last night
她就是在那遇到了凶手
and that that's where she met her killer.
我是这么想的
That's what I was thinking.
真奇怪  我们通常想法是一致的
Weird. We're usually more in sync than that.
莱恩
Hey, Ryan.
你在娜奥米的公寓找到什么了吗
Did you find anything at Naomi's apartment?
没有  但有人可能找到了
No, but someone else might have.
公寓被翻了个底朝天
It's been tossed.
不只这样  一个邻居说
Not only that, but a neighbor said
昨天很晚他们看到一个男的离开了公寓
they saw a man leaving the apartment late last night.
邻居通过素描确认了该男子
The neighbor I.D.'ed him off the sketch.
和逃离谋杀现场的是一个人
It's the same guy who fled the murder scene.
他在旅馆找不到自己想要的东西
He couldn't find what he was looking for in the motel
于是他去搜了她的住处
so he searched her place.
是啊  但这次他露了马脚
Yeah, but this time, he left a footprint.
你的意思是
Meaning?
巡逻警员根据这个素描
Well, units canvassed
在公寓周围进行了排查
around the apartment with the sketch.
他在隔几条街的地方用信用卡
He bought a bottle of single malt with a credit card
买了几瓶麦芽酒
a couple of blocks away.
科林·亨特  我们了解他什么
Colin Hunt. What do we have on him?
系统里什么都没有
Nothing in the system,
但是我从信用卡上查到了一些
but I ran a trace on the credit card.
他今天早上住进了蒙德里安苏豪酒店
He checked into the Mondrian SoHo this morning.
给你
Here.
纽约警察局  举起手来
NYPD. Show me your hands.
你们抓错人了
You're making a mistake.
我不是第一次听这种话了
Yeah, like I haven't heard that before.
举起手来
Hands in the air now.
如果你坚持要这样的话
If you insist.
喔  伙计
Whoa. Dude. Whoa.
自我介绍一下
Allow me to introduce myself.
科林·亨特警部  来自苏格兰场
Detective Inspector Colin Hunt, Scotland Yard.
你真是身在他乡啊  亨特警部
You're a long way from home, Detective Inspector Hunt.
你最怎么会出现在那女孩的旅馆房间
How did you end up in that dead girl's motel room ?
我昨晚在华盛顿开研讨会的时候
I was at a seminar in D.C. last night
娜奥米打电话给我  听起来很慌张
when Naomi called me, panicked.
她说她有麻烦了  需要我帮忙
She said she was in trouble and needed my help.
你认识她
So you knew her?
娜奥米就像我的妹妹一样
Naomi was like a sister to me.
她爸爸特伦斯是我当警察后的第一个搭档
Her dad Terence was my first partner on the job.
他去世的时候
When he passed away,
我答应她的家人会照顾好她
I promised her family that I'd look after her.
她打完电话  我就乘下一班飞机过来了
After she called me, I grabbed the next flight,
等我到的时候  已经太迟了
but by the time I arrived, it was too late.
你的第一反应是逃离犯罪现场
And your first instinct was to flee the crime scene?
我没有逃走  是离开
I didn't flee. I left.
她死了
She was dead.
我没什么能做的
There was nothing else to do.
是啊  除了到处转转
Yeah, except maybe to hang around
给警察做个口供
and give the police a statement.
你我都知道  如果我留在那
You and I both know that if I stuck around,
会是好几个小时的审问  之后你们就会
it'd be hours of questioning, and then you'd send me off
把我打发走说"谢谢你  保持联系"
with a "Cheers, we'll keep you posted."
但是我想你有更重要的事情要做
But I suppose you had something more important to do.
房间被搜索过了
The room had been searched.
杀她的人一定在找什么东西
Whoever killed her was looking for something.
我想他们接下来会去她的公寓
I thought they might try her apartment next.
等我到那  房间已经被搜过了
By the time I got there, it had already been tossed.
我知道我不应该被调查
Look, I know I shouldn't have been investigating,
但是如果你在国外
but if you were in a foreign country
你爱的人被杀了  你会怎么做
and someone you loved was killed, what would you do?
他们在找什么
What were they looking for?
执勤的时候  娜奥米的爸爸总是
When he was on a job, Naomi's dad used to stash a gun
在防弹衣内衬里藏把枪
in the lining of his Kevlar.
娜奥米少年时开始当模特之后
When Naomi started modeling as a teenager,
他不想让她坐地铁时没有任何保护
he didn't want her on the underground without any protection,
于是  他教她在夹克的内衬
So he taught her to cut a tiny piece
剪一个口放防狼喷雾
of the lining in her jacket to stash pepper spray.
我就是在那找到它的
That's where I found it.
你找到了什么
You found what?
一个指引我找到凶手的讯息
A message to me about her killer.
什么样的讯息
What kind of message?
让我办案才能告诉你
Not until I'm on the case.
你说什么
Excuse me?
探长  麻烦你
Detective, please,
我欠娜奥米的
I owe this to Naomi.
我欠她全家的
I owe it to her family.
你很清楚我可以因为你
You do realize that I could arrest you
隐瞒证据逮捕你吧
for withholding evidence?
既然你不知道证据是什么
And since you don't know what that evidence is,
我大可否认
I could deny it.
这么你来我往也抓不到杀她的凶手
And none of that will get us any closer to catching her killer.
让我和你们一起办案吧
Let me work this case with you,
我发誓  如果你不同意的话
because if you don't, I swear,
我会自己去抓住这个混蛋
I will go out there and catch the bastard on my own.
好吧
Okay.
但是我要先向警监请示一下
But I have to check in with my Captain first.
你们的警监人怎么样
What's she like, your Captain?
你看没看过视频网站上
You ever see that YouTube video
一只灰熊一巴掌
of the grizzly bear that decapitates a moose
拍死一只驼鹿的视频
with one swipe of its paw?
这比喻让我很"安心"
Comforting.
不是针对个别人
It's nothing personal.
她就是不喜欢外人来她的分局
She just doesn't like outsiders in her precinct.
我不需要她喜欢  我只要她能允许
I don't need her to like it. I just need her to allow it.
娜奥米的整件事情根本说不通
This whole thing with Naomi doesn't add up.
拒绝传统的模特工作
Turning down conventional modeling jobs,
而去接私人派对那种庸俗的活动
booking sleazy gigs at private parties--
凭我的了解  娜奥米不是这种人
that just doesn't sound like the Naomi I know.
有时候我们自以为了解某人
Yeah, well, sometimes it's the people we think we know best
结果却对她一无所知
that we don't really know at all.
算你一个
You're in.
谢谢
Thank you.
什么
What?
没搞错吧
Seriously?
你苏格兰场的主管
Yeah, your supervisor at Scotland Yard
说你是一名干探
said you're one of the best.
就连盖茨警监也对你的履历十分赞赏
Even Captain Gates was impressed with your record.
原来不是所有外人她都看不过眼
Well, I guess it's not outsiders she doesn't like.
只是讨厌我罢了
It's just me.
说话算话  娜奥米留给你的东西呢
Look, we had a deal. What did Naomi give you?
这个
This.
钥匙
A key?
你之前说的是信息
You said she left a message.
这就是信息
This is the message.
她有意留给我去找的
She put it in there for me to find.
我敢肯定这跟她的死有关
I guarantee, it has something to do with her death.
看着像商用钥匙
This looks commercial.
这是阿尔克·里夫金 11-30-r型号的
It's an Arco-Rifkin 11-30-r,
大多用于火车站或健身俱乐部的
mostly used for lockers like those found at train stations
储物柜
or health clubs.
好  我让莱恩在她公寓
All right, well, I'll have Ryan canvass
和汽车旅馆附近进行排查
the area around her apartment and the motel.
看有没有哪家店的储物柜
We'll see if any of the businesses have lockers
配了这种钥匙
that use this kind of key.
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
有发现
I got something.
这位是埃斯波西托警探
Uh, yeah, Detective Esposito,
这位是科林·亨特警部
This is Detective Inspector Colin Hunt.
来自苏格兰场
He's from Scotland Yard.
这件案子他也会参与调查
He's gonna be consulting on this case.
-他认识死者  -你好
- He knows our victim. - Hey. How's it going?
-幸会  -那你有什么发现
- Pleasure, mate. - So what do you got?
娜奥米昨晚确实参加了那个专辑发行派对
Well, Naomi did make it to that album release party last night
是在市中心的一家俱乐部
at a club in midtown,
但十点左右的时候她被保安赶了出来
but she was kicked out by security around 10:00.
为什么
Why?
她跟主办人发生了争执  是个饶舌女歌手
She had an altercation with the host, female rapper
也是前重罪犯妮基·杰
and ex-felon Nicky Jay.
她也不怕在狗仔队面前大打出手
And she wasn't afraid to take a swing in front of paparazzi.
为什么打起来
Wow. What was the fight about?
不清楚  但警员正带她回来问话
Unclear, but uniforms are bringing her up to interrogation now.
你们都是一个人问话吗
Do you usually question them solo?
不  一般都是我跟卡塞尔一起
No, Castle and I usually go in together.
要不这样吧  这次还是你俩来吧
Actually, you know what? Why don't you guys take this one?
你确定
Are you sure?
非常确定
Yeah, absolutely.
再说  这事关系到科林的朋友
Besides, Colin's got a personal interest.
-而不是我的  -好吧
- And I really don't now, do I? - Ah. All right.
-就这么定了  -好吧
- It's settled then. - Yeah, I guess it is.
而且我约了人吃午饭  她来了
Yeah, besides, my lunch date is here.
几个小时就回来
I'll be back in a few hours.
有眉目了就打电话给我
You guys call me if you find anything interesting.
见鬼  没错  我是打了她
Hell, yeah, I clocked her.
她想勾引我男人
She was trying to make a move on my man.
-是斯林大佬吗  -没错
- Your man Biggie Slim? - That's right.
她居然厚颜无耻的说他让她
She had the nerve to say that he told her
留个电话给他
to put her digits in his phone.
那他有没有
Did he?
这不是重点
That ain't the point!
那个贱女人根本就不该去
That skinny bitch wasn't even supposed to be there.
我找她对质的时候
When I got up in her face,
她说是斯林大佬的表弟德鲁让她来的
she said Biggie Slim's cousin Drew told her about the party.
但这就是扯淡  因为德鲁根本不在受邀之列
But I knew that was B.S. Because Drew wasn't even invited.
你男人到处沾花惹草
It must make you so bloody mad
你肯定很恼火吧
to know your man has a wandering eye.
我也交过这样的女朋友
I had a girlfriend like that.
到处出差
Traveled for business.
她从机场打来说航班取消了
She'd ring from the airport to say her flight was canceled.
我后来才发现  她劈腿了
I come to find out, she was seeing some other bloke.
听着她是个婊子
She sound like a ho.
我是想说  我理解你出于本能
All I'm saying is, I understand your instinct
痛扁你认为夺你所爱的人
to lash out at the person you believe is responsible.
防火防盗防小三  你也该跟姐学学
I protect what's mine. You should do the same.
所以这就尾随娜奥米去汽车旅馆
Is that why you followed Naomi to the motel
然后徒手把她勒死吗
and strangled her with your bare hands?
你嗑药了吧
You must be high.
那个贱人犯不着我浪费那个时间
That skank wasn't worth another second of my time.
我叫保安赶她出去
I told security to give her the boot,
仅此而已
and that was that.
是吗  你能证明吗
Really? Can you prove it?
我司机送我们回的家
My driver brought us home.
然后整晚我都跟斯林大佬在一起
And I was with Biggie Slim the rest of the night.
对  我跟妮基·杰一起回的家
Yeah, I went home with Nicky Jay.
打完人之后  她情绪很激动
After the tussle, she was all worked up.
但我喜欢她这样
But I like it when she gets worked up,
拼命想证明我是她的
when she got something to prove.
她说动手的原因是因为
She said that the fight started because you were
你在跟她搭讪
spending time with this girl.
对  这个妞儿
Oh, yeah, that girl.
能说什么呢
Hey, what can I say?
我貌比潘安  才比子建  哪个女人抵挡得住
Women are powerless against my good looks and charms.
真是残忍的诅咒啊
Yes, it's a real curse.
你和娜奥米  你们谈什么了
You and Naomi-- what did you talk about?
东拉西扯呗
Ah, a little bit of this, a little bit of that.
这妞不咋的
She was a bad chick, you know?
有点疯  你懂我意思吗
But a little off. You know what I'm talking about?
不懂  说明白点
No, what are you talkin' about?
她有点妄想症
I mean, she was acting paranoid, man,
说有人尾随她到派对
said somebody had followed her to the party.
我以为她在编故事呢
I figured she was just blowing smoke.
为什么
Why is that?
我不仅仅在包装妮基·杰
Look, I don't just produce Nicky Jay, all right?
还在建立自己的品牌
I'm building my brand.
我有斯林大佬唱片公司  有斯林大佬服饰
I got Biggie Slim records, Biggie Slim clothing.
甚至还生产了斯林大佬能量饮料
Hell, I even got a Biggie Slim energy drink.
所以有妹子过来求关注
So some filly comes up trying to make her time,
我都见怪不怪了
it's just a everyday thing in my life.
她说没说她觉得是被谁跟踪了
Did she tell you who she thought was following her?
没有
Sure didn't.
不过看来她是没撒谎
I guess she wasn't lying, though, huh?
娜奥米离开派对后
Naomi left that party
三小时后就死了
and then three hours later, she was dead.
根据她对斯林大佬所说的
Based on what she told Biggie Slim,
娜奥米知道自己被跟踪了
Naomi knew somebody was after her.
在派对举办地周围排查一下
All right, let's canvass the area around the party venue,
看她是否真的被跟踪了
see if she was being followed.
再找来妮基·杰和斯林大佬的司机
And let's track down Nicky Jay and Biggie Slim's driver.
确认他们是否真的直接回家了
I want to see if they went straight home.
这就去办
On it.
你跟妮基·杰讲的关于你女朋友的故事
So... that story that you told Nicky Jay about your girlfriend...
胡扯的
Total pants.
就是想让她以为我同情她
I just wanted her to think I sympathized.
说实话  见过了斯林大佬
And honestly, after meeting Biggie Slim,
我是真同情她
I do.
或许她一直在等
Well, maybe she's hanging on,
希望他会改变
hoping that he'll change.
他这样的人永远不会改变
Guys like him never do.
法医已经验尸完毕
Our M.E.'s finished the autopsy.
她喉部被挤碎
Her larynx is crushed.
凶手一定很强壮
Whoever did it was strong.
手掌很大  很有可能是男性
Large hands, probably a male.
这把半个城的人都涵盖了
That's like half the city.
我们还能再把范围缩小一些
We may be able to narrow it down a little further than that.
凶手力道很大
The pressure from the killer's grip
在她脖子上留下了指纹
left a print on her neck.
能把指纹提取出来吗
Were you able to pull a print?
幸亏她擦了乳液
We recovered a partial
我们恢复了部分指纹
thanks to the body lotion she was wearing.
系统里有这枚指纹吗
Is it in the system?
没法进行搜索  不过要是能有
Not enough to run it, but you bring me a print
嫌犯的指纹  我能验证它们是否吻合
off a suspect, I can tell you if it's a match.
不好意思  我得打个电话
Excuse me. I have to make a call.
长得不错
Easy on the eyes.
口音也很迷人
Cute accent, too.
我就问你一件事
I just got one question.
卡塞尔在哪
Where's Castle?
他走了
He took off...
去赴一个午餐约会
for a lunch date.
跟那个开他的法拉利的空姐吗
In a Ferrari full of flight attendant?
是啊  估计是想多累积点
Yeah, he's probably trying to rack up
航空积分里程
his frequent flyer miles.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
不过你知道她只不过是过眼烟云
But you know she's just a passing thing.
是吗  这家伙都离婚两次了
Do I? I mean, the guy has been divorced twice,
还去跟大胸女鬼混
and he's still chasing bimbos.
或许这就是他的本性
Maybe that's just who he is.
也许时机不对
Look, maybe it's the wrong time
也或许他不是真命天子
or maybe he's even the wrong guy,
可如果他是
but if he is,
你要等多久才肯去问明白
how long are you gonna wait to find out?
十年了  我陪这些被害人
Ten years, I've been keeping them company
度过一两个晚上
while they spend a night or two here
然后他们就会化为灰尘  人终有一死
on their way to where we're all going.
他们都曾有自己的规划  凯特
They all had plans, Kate,
都有腾出空来就会做的事
things they were gonna do when they got around to it--
坐次游轮  减个九斤体重  谈个恋爱
go on a cruise, lose 10 pounds, fall in love.
他们本以为自己有大把时间
They thought they had all the time in the world.
但却事与愿违
But nobody does.
看到自己亲近的人出事确实很难过
The personal ones are tough.
你不是出来打电话的
No call.
你怎么看出来的
What's my tell?
你沉思的身影
The brooding lean.
是啊
Ah, yes.
我真菜
Rookie move.
她以前满嘴戴着牙箍
You know, even with a mouth full of braces,
也还是班里最漂亮的女孩子
she was the prettiest girl in her class.
有个警察父亲
Although having a cop for a dad
对她的社交生活没啥帮助
didn't do much for her social life.
她的约会对象们送她回家时
Terry used to interrogate her dates
特伦总是各种审问他们
when they'd drop her off.
那些轻量级选手肯定就此淘汰了
I could see how that would weed out the lightweights.
她22岁的时候
And then when she was 22,
爱上了一名年轻的医生  他是个好人
she fell in love with a young doctor, good guy.
去年他在非洲行医的时候去世了
He died last year in Africa doing god's work.
我觉得她一直都没有从阴影里走出来
I don't think she ever really got over it,
因为听了那么多她做的事情
because hearing what she was up to,
感觉她好像完全变了个人
it's like she was a different person.
人总是在你不经意间就发生了变化
People change when you're not looking.
不好意思
Excuse me.
莱恩  怎么了
Hey, Ryan. What's up?
你确定
Are you sure?
在哪
Where?
好的  很好  申请搜查令
Okay, great. Call in a warrant.
他们在汽车旅馆旁找到一家健身房
They found a gym near the motel.
娜奥米被害当晚在那买了一张一日通票
Naomi bought a day pass there the night that she was killed,
员工说她进去之后三分钟就出来了
and the clerk said she was in and out in three minutes.
这时间刚好够她把东西藏在
Just enough time to run in and hide something
某个储物箱里
in one of the lockers.
她在晚上10点24分买的一日通票
She bought the day pass at 10:24 P.M.
正好是在打电话向我求救的二十分钟之后
That's 20 minutes after she called me to say she was in trouble.
她是给我留下了一条信息
She was leaving me a message.
她不仅仅给我们留下了有关凶手的信息
She did better than leave a message about the killer.
还给我们留下了他的照片
She left us a picture of him as well.
序列号搜索有结果吗
Anything on the number sequence?
我在搜索所有的数据库
We're running it through every database,
目前还没有结果
but nothing so far.
娜奥米不会无故留下这条信息
Naomi wrote it on there for a reason.
照片那头有线索吗
What about the photo?
从光线和背景建筑来看
Well, based on the light and background architecture,
这张照片是在纽约市中心拍的
this photo was taken in midtown New York.
我错过什么了吗
Hey. What did I miss?
没什么
Not much.
我们只不过找到了那个神秘的储物箱
Oh, we did manage to find that mystery locker.
还有那张照片里的男子
And that guy in the photo,
他很有可能是凶手
he's probably our killer.
午饭吃得怎么样
So, how was your lunch?
爱死那里的特色菜了
Oh, I loved the special.
必须的
I'll bet.
等等
Wait a minute.
能放大这块区域吗
Can you blow up this one section?
当然
Yeah, sure.
金色的圆状物  是块匾额
Rounded and gold? It's a plaque.
是英国的标志
It's the British seal.
这张照片是在英国领事馆外拍的
This picture was taken right outside the British Consulate.
把领事馆的雇员名单调出来
Pull up a list of the Consulate employees.
好了
Here you go.
不在这页
Well, he's not on this page.
就是他
There he is.
奈吉尔·温德姆
Nigel Wyndham.
英国领事馆的副总领事
Deputy general of the British Consulate.
也就是说论官职  他仅次于总领事
Which means he's just under the Consulate General in rank,
负责财政以及后勤方面的
so he's responsible for the daily operations
日常事务
in financial and logistical matters.
娜奥米怎么会跟这家伙扯上关系
What the hell was Naomi doing mixed up with this guy?
我跟一位苏格兰场的朋友联系了一下
That was my mate at Scotland Yard.
他发现一些跟奈吉尔·温德姆有关的怪事
He found out some intriguing details on Nigel Wyndham,
他的一个大学女友在他们
like the fact that a girlfriend in college
去罗马度假
died rather mysteriously
的时候神秘死亡
while they were on holiday in Rome.
他受过起诉吗
Well, was he ever charged?
没有  之后他还牵扯进一系列案件调查
No, and after that, he had a string of bad investments
直到他娶了辛西娅·沃德罗
until he married Cynthia Wadlow.
她用自己显赫的家世
It was her prominent family
动用关系才给他谋了个职位
who pulled strings that got him a position,
首先是文化部部长
first at the Ministry of Culture,
后来就到领事馆来了
and then here at the Consulate.
我们一直在溯查娜奥米几周前到
So we've been reconstructing Naomi's movements
纽约后的所有行程
since she landed in New York a couple of weeks ago.
她的财务记录显示  她上周约了辆车
Her financials indicate that she booked a car service last week
送她去"信"料理[知名日本餐厅]
that dropped her at Nobu.
我们刚才给店主看了奈吉尔的照片
Now we showed the host Nigel's picture,
他很确定俩人在那儿见过面
and he confirmed that they met for dinner.
店主注意到什么细节吗
Did the host notice anything?
有  他注意到了奈吉尔用来预定后排雅座的
Yeah, he noticed the c-note that Nigel dropped
那张百元钞票了
to secure the romantic table in the back.
各位
Hey.
我刚刚电话联系了领事馆
I just called the consulate.
在"信"料理那顿浪漫会面的前一天
The day after the romantic Nobu dinner,
娜奥米被保安从奈吉尔的办公室里赶出来了
security removed Naomi from Nigel's office.
感觉应该是吵架了
Well, it sounds like a fight.
保安说在送娜奥米出去的时候听见她
Uh, security heard Naomi yell something about Cynthia
喊着辛西娅的一些事
as they escorted her out.
那就都说得通了
Well, it makes perfect sense.
身处一段毫无感情的婚姻
Stuck in a marriage of convenience,
奈吉尔邂逅了年轻漂亮的娜奥米
Nigel meets the young and beautiful Naomi,
发现她的美令人无法抗拒
finds her irresistible.
邂逅变成了晚宴  晚宴变成了幽会
A chance meeting turns to dinner, dinner to a tryst,
但娜奥米并不满足
but then Naomi wants more.
奈吉尔意识到他的出轨会威胁到
Nigel realizes that his affair has become a threat
他的事业  他的声誉  和他倚仗
to his position, his reputation, to the life he built
妻子一家人而得到的生活
on the backs of his wife and her family.
长官  如果奈吉尔的妻子发现他出轨的话
Sir, if Nigel's wife found out about an affair,
他的婚姻和事业就全毁了
it would kill his marriage and his career.
亨特警部
Detective Inspector Hunt,
你一言不发是因为你有别的看法吗
I take your silence to mean that you don't agree?
我认识的那个娜奥米
Well, the Naomi I knew
绝对不会倾心于温德姆这种人
would never fall for someone like Wyndham,
但如果这个人跟她的死没关系的话
but she wouldn't have left his picture in that locker
她肯定不会把这张照片留在储物柜里
if he weren't connected to her death somehow.
奈吉尔·温德姆在领事馆的职位
Nigel Wyndham's position at the consulate
是享受外交豁免权的
includes diplomatic immunity.
但如果他是命案嫌疑人的话就无效了
Which would be waived if he was a suspect in a murder case.
如果我拿起电话提出审查请求的话
If I pick up the phone to make that request,
我需要一些比猜想更有说服力的东西
I'm gonna need something more concrete than just a theory.
长官  蕾妮在被害人的脖子上
Sir, Lanie pulled our killer's prints
已经提取到了凶手的指纹
off of our victim's neck.
根据我们目前掌握的所有情况来看
And given everything that we know right now,
我敢打赌那就是奈吉尔的指纹
I am willing to bet that they're a match to Nigel's.
赌是不够的
A bet's not enough.
但如果你能弄到指纹
But if you can get those prints,
那就另说了
then this is a whole different conversation.
麻烦来了  兄弟
Here's the problem, bro--
外国高官不会在当地的执法部门那里
Foreign dignitaries don't register their fingerprints
登记自己的指纹
with local law enforcement.
如果我们向领事馆提出申请的话
And if we put in a request to the consulate,
他们会把拒绝我们的请求
they'll box us out
奈吉尔也就知道他现在是杀人嫌犯了
and alert Nigel that he's a suspect.
是啊  我还以为苏格兰场能弄到指纹呢
Yeah, I thought Scotland Yard would be able to get them.
即便他在英国有关系  我们还是走到了死胡同
Even with his connections across the pond, we struck out.
伙计们  看好了
Okay, boys. Here it is.
看什么
Here's what?
用来获取奈吉尔指纹的完美计划
My foolproof plan for getting Nigel's fingerprint.
奈吉尔住在公园大道的
Nigel lives in a high-rise apartment
一栋高级公寓里
here on Park Avenue.
对  安保级别也很高
Yeah. High security.
没错  莱恩  你到时候在这里
Exactly. Ryan, you'll be here--
前门  扮成一个送花的快递员
Front door-- dressed as a flower delivery boy.
埃斯波西托  你扮成流浪汉到这里
Esposito, you'll be here dressed as a hobo.
我有疑问
Question.
为啥得是棕色皮肤的人来扮流浪汉
Why's the brown man gotta be a hobo?
你想送花吗
You want the flowers?
那还是流浪汉吧
Hobo it is.
你俩在这里负责吸引注意
You boys will cause a distraction here
而我和尼克莱一起从大楼的这边
whilst I rappel down the side of the building
-迂回过来  -尼克莱是谁
- with Nicolai. - Who's Nicolai?
是我在YouTube上找到的一个罗马尼亚体操运动员
He's a Romanian gymnast I found on YouTube.
他的身体柔韧性非常好
He's extremely flexible
可以藏在野营包里
and fits in the duffel bag.
再利用一把玻璃刀
Using a glass cutter...
打扰一下  各位  我能
Excuse me, gents. I can--
有谁见到贝克特探长了吗
Has anyone seen Detective Beckett?
你俩这是要去约会吗
You guys going out?
我找了些关系  让我俩今晚能去
I pulled some strings and got us into a party
参加英国领事馆的一个宴会
at the British consulate tonight.
奈吉尔也会参加
Nigel will be there.
我们会神不知鬼不觉地弄到他的指纹
We'll get his prints, and he won't even know it.
告辞了  各位
Cheers, lads.
慢走
Cheers.
除了你那招也可以那样干
Or they could do that.
是哦
Yeah, sure,
前提是你喜欢用技术含量低的法子
if you want to do it the easy way.
多谢
Thank you.
阿尔弗雷德·希斯爵士是谁啊
So who is Sir Alfred Heath?
今天晚上是我
Tonight, I am.
国内的同事说真正的阿尔弗雷德爵士
The lads back home said the real Sir Alfred
肯定来不了
is down as a no-show.
因为痛风还是什么病来着
Gout or some damn thing.
万一奈吉尔·温德姆也不来呢
Yeah, but what if Nigel Wyndham doesn't show either?
他肯定会来的
He'll be here.
我猜他不会喝香槟
And I expect he'll skip the champagne
而是直接上高档的
and drink something posh and pretentious,
这样的话杯子上就有指纹了
leaving his print on the glass.
万一他不喝酒呢
Well, what if he doesn't drink?
他是英国人
He's British.
相信我  他肯定好这口
Trust me, he drinks.
我能邀请你吗
May I?
我没想到这次行动还要跳舞
I didn't realize that dancing was a part of the plan.
这样可以比较好地监视目标
It offers a perfect vantage point.
你经常参加这种活动吗
Do you come to a lot of these events?
当然没有  怎么了
No, thank God. Why?
你好像很自信的样子
You just seem very confident.
那是因为我的女伴
Well, that's because my companion
是这里最美丽最耀眼的女人
is the most beautiful woman in this room.
你这显然是喝醉了胡说
That's clearly the champagne talking.
我相信你在这里感觉很自在
I'm sure you're just comfortable here
因为周围都是你们的人
because you're amongst your own people.
他们才不是我们的人
These aren't my people.
我们的人都在端盘子送酒呢
My people are the ones carrying the trays.
没错
Yeah.
我是在伦敦东区[贫民区]长大的
I grew up on the east end.
我妈妈给别人打扫屋子  我爸爸在工厂上班
My mom cleaned flats. Dad worked in a factory.
他们都想要更好的生活  可他们就是
They wanted something better, they just--
他们就是得不到
They couldn't quite get it.
然后呢
And then?
我拿到的伊顿公学的奖学金
I was admitted to Eton on a scholarship
在那里我试着融入他们
where I minored in blending in.
你呢
What about you?
我在纽约长大
I grew up in the city
去加州念的大学
and, uh, went to college in California.
显然你可以做任何
Well, you could obviously do anything
你想做的事情
you put your mind to.
为啥要当警察呢
Why be a cop?
我猜这就是我的使命吧
I guess it was just my calling.
啊  你是个正义战士呢
Ah, a crusader.
我知道这种类型
I know the type.
但是一心工作  私人生活就遭殃了  是吧
Doesn't leave a lot of time for personal life, though, does it?
那你呢  你也是正义战士吗
What about you? Are you the crusader type as well?
我恐怕已经把工作当成老婆了
Married to the bit, I'm afraid.
工作总是放在首位
The job comes first.
只是有时候  我真希望不是这样
Though sometimes, I wish it didn't.
是啊  我知道这种感觉
Yeah. I know the feeling.
等一下  看吧台那边
Wait a minute. Look over there by the bar.
一点钟方向
At one o'clock.
游戏开始吧
Let the games begin.
晚上好
Good evening.
奈吉尔·温德姆  副总管
Nigel Wyndham. Deputy general.
简恩·哈灵顿
Jean Harrington.
无聊啊
Bored.
那我们来找点乐子吧  哈灵顿小姐
Well, we'll have to remedy that, Ms. Harrington.
给这位女士一杯酒
Uh, one for the lady, please.
你结婚了  真扫兴
Oh, a ring. That's discouraging.
没必要扫兴
Oh, well, it needn't be.
为新友谊干杯
To new friendships.
哈灵顿女士  你是独自一人来的吗
Now tell me, Ms. Harrington, are you here alone?
如果是的话  真是天理难容
If so, it would be a grave injustice.
我的伴侣比起我更喜欢社交
My date's more interested in networking than he is in me.
那么我想他不会介意
In that case, he won't object
我请你跳舞吧
if I ask you for a dance.
你知道吗
You know what?
就算他介意我也不管
I wouldn't care even if he did.
那我们来吧
Shall we?
跟我说说  哈灵顿女士
So... tell me, Ms. Harrington,
你是个什么样的人
What should I know about you?
光关注眼前所见的可不够哦
Well, there's more to me than meets the eye.
眼前所见的
Well, what meets the eye
真是让人难以抗拒
is irresistible.
知道吗  行动胜于空谈
You know, actions speak louder than words.
什么意思
Meaning?
我是说  如果真是难以抗拒
Meaning, if I'm so irresistible,
那你为何不用两只手跳舞呢
then why aren't you using both your hands?
失陪了  阁下
Excuse me, your excellency.
对不起  借过
Oh, excuse me. Pardon me.
借过一下
Coming through.
-对不起  先生  别动  - 真鲁莽
- Sorry, sir. As you were. -  Very rude!
借过
Excuse me. Oh. Oh!
Excuse me.
您是阿尔弗雷德·希斯爵士吗
Sir Alfred Heath?
是的
Yes.
能借一步说话吗  先生
Might I have a word, sir?
今晚似乎真假爵士都出席了
There seems to be two of you here this evening.
我不得不问
I-I have to ask,
你在做其他事情时也像在舞池
Are you as aggressive in your other activities
一样主动吗
as you are on the dance floor?
怎么说呢
Ah, you know, what can I say?
我总是喜欢掌控局面
I like to lead... all the time.
你们一定弄错了
Well, there's obviously been a serious mistake.
我真是阿尔弗雷德爵士
I am the real Sir Alfred,
一切都好吗
Is--is everything all right?
是的  只是我突然...
Um, yeah. You know, I'm suddenly--
突然觉得很饿  不好意思
I feel very hungry. Excuse me.
你想尝一口吗  听说很美味
Would you like one of these? I hear they're great.
我不大喜欢鱼子酱
I'm not a caviar man myself.
这样啊  不过我听说它们可以激发欲望的
Yeah, but I hear they're an aphrodisiac.
对我没啥用  我恐怕
Mm. Not for me, I'm afraid.
抱歉打断二位  温德姆先生
I'm sorry to intrude, Mr. Wyndham, sir.
什么事  布莱森
Yes, what is it, Bryson?
这位年轻女士  我需要她跟我们走一趟
Uh, the young lady, I need her to come with me.
为什么
Well, for what purpose?
别担心  亲爱的
Don't worry, darling.
我们能很快重逢的
I know that we'll see each other again very soon.
我本盯住那侍者了  结果跟丢了
I had the waiter, then I lost him.
我把整个计划毁了
I've bollixed up the whole plan,
现在我们一无所获
and now we've got nothing.
我可不会这么说
Oh, I wouldn't say nothing.
我偷来了温德姆的卡套
I swiped Wyndham's card case.
上面布满他的指纹
It's got his prints all over it.
你真是个狡猾的小偷
You sneaky little thief.
太他妈聪明了
That's bloody brilliant.
多谢夸奖  现在去让这混蛋显形吧
Thank you. Now let's go get this son of a bitch.
指纹比对不上
The print's not a match.
说啥
What?
鉴证组鉴定了卡套上的指纹
C.S.U. ran the fingerprints off the card case,
拿它与蕾妮在娜奥米尸体上发现的指纹比对
compared 'em to the one that Lanie found on Naomi's body.
那指纹不是奈吉尔·温德姆的
It wasn't Nigel Wyndham's.
这不可能  再去查一遍
No, that's not possible. Run it again.
莱恩已经反复查过三遍了
Ryan already did that three times.
温德姆不是凶手
Wyndham's not our killer.
他肯定脱不了干系  我很清楚
He's behind this. I know it.
所以娜奥米才给我们留下他的照片
It's why Naomi left us his photograph.
也许他雇佣了某人来替他做杀人的勾当
Well, maybe he hired someone to do his dirty work for him.
比如他的安保人员
Like one of his security men.
你能让苏格兰场的同事查查
Can you get Scotland Yard to run background checks
他安保人员的底细吗
on the security staff?
或许更好方法是从娜奥米在照片背面
Or a better path might be to look into this mysterious number
留下的神秘数字入手
that Naomi wrote on the back of that photo,
这个谜团已经被解开了
Which is a mystery, no longer.
这是龙虾吗  老兄
Is this lobster, bro?
算你走运  贾辛达胃口很小
Lucky for you, Jacinda's a light eater.
把它加热一下  再配上点黄油酱...
You heat that up, little bit of melted butter--
你是说你知道那串数字的含义吗  怎么知道的
Are you telling us you know what that number means? How?
当我和贾辛达正在享用
Well, as Jacinda and I were enjoying
鲜美的缅因州龙虾大餐时
our succulent lobsters from Maine,
配上朴实而高雅的
paired with an earthy
索诺玛谷[法国]的黑比诺葡萄酒
yet elegant Pinot Noir from Sonoma Valley--
卡塞尔  说数字
Castle, numbers.
对  我们当时在查看文件
Right. Well, we were going over the file.
发现贾辛达竟然是个破案达人
Turns out Jacinda's quite a little crime solver.
你给那空姐看证据文件了
You showed the stewardess the evidence file?
没有
No.
我只是用手机拍了张照而已
I took a picture of it with my phone.
而且你应当称呼人家"飞机乘务员"
And the preferred nomenclature is "Flight attendant."
关键在于  这串代码
The point is, this code refers to
代表了一个外交邮包
a diplomatic pouch.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know that?
贾辛达认出了这个格式
Jacinda recognized the format.
而且她还告诉我最后三位数字
Furthermore, she told me these last three digits
代表了皇家东方航空
are a reference code for Royal Eastern Airlines.
说明那外交邮包就是通过该航空公司寄送的
Which means the pouch was delivered on that airline.
正是  "W4"代表了邮袋的尺寸
Exactly. The "W4" refers to the size of the pouch,
"1949"则是该物件在领事馆邮包的
the "1949" indicates exactly which pouch it is
序列编号
in the consulate sequence.
作为副总管  奈吉尔签发所有的邮包
As the deputy general, Nigel signs for all the pouches.
就是说这也许不是因为奈吉尔和娜奥米的
So then maybe this wasn't about an affair gone wrong
婚外情出了岔子
between Nigel and Naomi.
-这事关走私  -这样就说得通了
- It's about smuggling. - Well, that makes a lot of sense.
外交邮包是密封的  所含之物
Diplomatic pouches are sealed and their contents
免于运输局和海关检查
bypass T.S.A. and customs inspections.
娜奥米一定是发现了温德姆的违法勾当
Naomi must have got on to what Wyndham was doing somehow.
我们得弄清那邮包里有什么
We need to know what was in that pouch.
领事馆是绝不会告诉我们的
The consulate's never gonna release that information.
无需通过领事馆
Oh, we don't have to worry about the consulate.
航空公司有货运单的副本
The airline keeps a copy of the waybill.
联系航空公司  拿到那份货运单
Get ahold of the airline. Let's get that waybill down here.
莱恩  拿支笔
Ryan, grab a pen.
怎么了
What?
卡塞尔  你不能把警方的
Castle, you can't just share
保密信息泄露给外人
confidential police information with an outsider.
即使这助我们破案吗
Even if it solves the case?
她给了我们条线索
I mean, she gave us a lead.
比你在领事馆查到的信息更有价值
That's more than you got at the consulate.
那你这么做就可以了吗
And that's supposed to make this all okay?
贾辛达纯属好意  有什么大不了的
Jacinda just wanted to help. What's the big deal?
你不明白  对吗
You don't get it, do you?
我想我是不明白
No, I guess I don't.
我想你也不明白
No, I gu-- I guess you don't.
我查到些线索  来看看
We found something you're gonna want to see.
航空公司把货运单传过来了
The airline e-mailed over the waybill.
与这个货号吻合的邮包
The pouch that matches our number
是一年前从英国领事馆寄出
was shipped from the British Consulate about a year ago.
从肯尼迪国际机场
It flew from J.F.K.
寄往达乌干达的坎帕拉[首都]
to Kampala, Uganda.
乌干达  这不会是巧合
Uganda? That can't be a coincidence.
什么意思
What do you mean?
娜奥米已故的男友  就是在乌干达遇害
Naomi's boyfriend, the one who died, he was killed in Uganda.
知道是什么货物吗
Any idea of what was being shipped?
只知道重达181斤
Uh, just that it weighed 200 pounds.
对于邮包而言  这货不轻啊
Well, that's awfully heavy for a pouch.
外交邮包小到一个信封
Well, a diplomatic pouch can be as small as an envelope
大到货物集装箱都有
or as big as a cargo container.
不管是什么  每月寄送一次
Whatever's being shipped, it's being sent out about once a month.
我彻查了去年整年的航空货运单
I just combed through airline waybills from the past year.
还有十个同样重量的邮包
Ten other pouches, all the same weight,
都是从这里寄往乌干达
were flown from here to Uganda.
其中一件显示
In fact, one of them is listed
存放在肯尼迪国际机场的行李区
as being in J.F.K.'s Secure Baggage Area.
你的意思是  其中一个邮包
You mean to say, one of those pouches
现在还在机场
is at the airport right now?
弄清邮包里的货物
Finding out what's in that pouch
有助于我们找到杀死娜奥米的凶手
could tell us who killed Naomi.
对  可卡塞尔  我们没有管辖权
Yeah, but we don't have any jurisdiction here, Castle.
如果纽约警察擅自打开英国外交邮包的话
If the NYPD tries to open up a British diplomatic pouch,
很可能引发国际争端
we could risk an international incident.
值得庆幸的是  我可不是纽约警察
Then it's a good thing I'm not NYPD.
晚上好
Good evening, sir.
我是国土安全局的鲍尔探员
I'm agent Bauer with Homeland Security.
我是来检查的
I'm here for the inspection.
没人通知我有任何检查
Nobody radioed me about any inspection.
当然没人通知你
Well, of course they didn't.
我们随机抽查以评估安保系统
We conduct random checks to assess security.
提前通知就与我们的目的相触了
Telling you we were coming kind of defeats the purpose.
我说的对吧
Am I right?
那就是泄露了天机
We'd be tipping our hand, showing our play book, so to speak.
我在这个班点工作两年了
Two years, I've worked this shift,
从没听说过什么
and I've never heard of anything--
摩根对吧  我相信你这儿管理严格
Look, Morgan, is it? I'm sure you run a tight ship here.
所以如果里面没问题
So if things inside are secure,
我保证去跟你老板说
I'll make damn sure your bosses know about it,
这是给你脸上贴金
which will reflect well on you.
朋友  我们是一条船上的
We're all on the same team here, pal.
我得和我上司确认下
I gotta verify this with my supervisor.
好吧  请便
Yeah, you do that.
忽悠人  我越来越老练了
I'm getting more adept at faking my way past people.
肯定是熟能生巧
Must be all the practice.
你在行李区了吗
You're in the Baggage Area?
嗯  但我时间紧迫
Yeah, but I don't have much time.
在他发现我胡扯之前
Maybe a minute before the guy calls his supervisor
我还有一分钟
to check my story.
根据货号对应信息
All right, so based on the shipping code,
你要找的邮包
the pouch that you're looking for
大概一米半长
is about 5 feet long.
货运单有说是板条箱  军用提箱
Does the waybill say if it's a crate, a footlocker,
还是纸板箱什么的吗
cardboard box, what?
抱歉兄弟  上面没有
No, sorry, bro.
但它重达181斤
But it's 200 pounds,
肯定挺结实的
so it's gotta be something sturdy.
结实  好吧
Something sturdy. Right.
我找到了  是个板条箱
Here we go. I found it. It's a crate.
鲍尔探员
Agent Bauer!
请你出来
I need you to step outta there, please.
听起来情况不妙
Okay, that didn't sound good.
说自己叫鲍尔  能不被拆穿吗
Agent Bauer-- what did he expect?
我听到了
I heard that.
我就好
I've just about wrapped up here.
先生  我上司快来了
Sir, my supervisor will be here--
他会非常满意你的工作的  摩根
And he will be mighty pleased with your work, Morgan,
非常满意
Mighty pleased.
依我看  你努力程度堪比
It's clear to me that you've been working harder than a...
参加踢人比赛里的独腿龙
one-legged man in an ass-kicking contest.
快点出来  我不会再重复了
Step outta there now, sir. I will not tell you again.
喂
Hello!
你还在里面吗  喂
You there? Hello!
我的天啊
Bloody hell.
板条箱里是什么
What's in the crate?
是导弹
Missiles.
海关和国土安全局已将板条箱扣留
Customs and Homeland Security have impounded the crate,
国际刑警正赶往肯尼迪国际机场
and Interpol is on their way to J.F.K.
你打算怎么解释私自打开外交邮包的事
How did you explain opening the diplomatic pouch?
此时此刻大家对导弹更有兴趣
Well, everyone's more interested in the missiles at the moment,
但我猜是祸躲不过
but I expect I'll be in hot water at some point.
那温德姆呢
And where does this leave Wyndham?
毫发无伤
Untouched.
怎么会  他在走私军火
What do you mean untouched? He was smuggling weapons.
当然他们会对他进行盘问
Well, they'll have an inquiry, of course,
可他们不能证明他知道板条箱里是什么
but they can't prove he knew what was in the crate.
而且鉴于我们非法打开板条箱
And since we opened the crate illegally,
它不能作为合法证据
we won't be able to use it as evidence.
至少现在有点头绪了
At least it all starts to make sense now.
娜奥米想查出艾登被害的真正原因
Naomi was trying to solve Aiden's murder.
也就是娜奥米的男友艾登·米勒
That would be Naomi's boyfriend--Aiden Miller.
他随无国界医生在乌干达行医
He worked for Doctors Without Borders in Uganda
直到一年前他的直升飞机
until his helicopter was shot down
被游击部队击落
by guerilla forces a year ago.
英国政府对此进行调查
The British government launched an investigation,
但他们一直想不通叛军是如何弄到
but was never able to determine how the rebels acquired
防空导弹的
a stinger missile.
现在我们知道是奈吉尔·温德姆提供的
Which we now know came to them courtesy of Nigel Wyndham.
但是奈吉尔不是那种
Yeah, except Nigel's not the type
会亲自去捣腾导弹或者杀人的人
to get his hands dirty when it comes to missiles or murder.
他肯定有个能获悉防空导弹情报的同伙
He must have had a partner who had a line on those stingers.
如果娜奥米开始查探走私的勾当
And if Naomi started looking into the smuggling operation...
那就有可能是他的搭档杀死了她
Then perhaps it was the partner who got rid of her.
问题是  他的搭档是谁
So then the question is, who is this partner?
娜奥米所做的每件事都是为了
Everything Naomi did was about finding out
查到谁提供了杀死她男友的军火
who supplied the weapon that killed her boyfriend.
这也是她不接模特工作的原因
That's why she stopped taking modeling gigs.
是她来纽约的原因
That's why she came to New York. It's...
或许是某个在外国特权派对
Maybe there's someone on that list of attendees
名单上的出席者
for that, uh, foreign dignitary party.
我是说一切都开始于几个月前她去伦敦的
I mean, it all started when she booked that out of london
那次模特工作
A few months ago.
保罗·莫库兹
Paulo Makuzi.
他是谁
And who is he?
乌干达反叛军的一个首领
A leader of the rebel army in Uganda.
娜奥米一定是在派对上听到了什么细节
Naomi must have heard something at the party.
才把她引到领事馆
That's what led her to the consulate.
跟奈吉尔的浪漫晚餐只是她为了从他办公室
And that romantic dinner with Nigel was just part of her agenda
拿到包裹号码的计划之一
to get the pouch number from his office.
那么她的调查只有
So then there's just one piece
一个细节解释不通了
that doesn't fit in her investigation.
她找斯林大佬干什么
What was she doing with Biggie Slim?
我要你仔细看看这张照片
I want you to take a close look at this photo.
我见过这张
Yeah, I've seen this one.
狗仔队两周前拍到我和妮基·杰
Paparazzi caught me and Nicky Jay
从录音棚出来
coming out of the studio a couple weeks ago.
那是妮基·杰的黑色SUV  是吗
In fact, that is Nicky Jay's black s.U.V., isn't it?
是我斯林大佬买给她的
Bought by Biggie Slim himself.
供需关系嘛  她要我就给
Supply and demand. She demands, I gotta supply.
有一件事我觉得很有趣
You know, the thing that I find intriguing
在你成为斯林大佬之前
is that before you became Biggie Slim,
你名叫达利斯·杨
you're name was Darius Young,
不过是个开办了几个没成功的网络公司的小人物
best known for launching several failed internet start-ups.
都是陈年旧事了
Just a man ahead of my time.
美国证监会认为你是一个
Well, the S.E.C. thought you were a man
诈骗投资人的骗子
trying to fleece investors.
但是我从来没有被起诉
See, I was never charged for that.
有一项投资
One of your ventures,
一个在英国的音乐分享网站
a music sharing web site based in the U.K.,
受到了英国政府的关注
caught the attention of British authorities.
在他们打算关闭网站的时候
And when they tried to shut it down,
一份替你说情的文件寄到了文化部长手中
an aide to the minister of culture lobbied on your behalf.
你知道提供帮助的人是谁吗
And do you know who that aide was?
奈吉尔·温德姆
Nigel Wyndham.
事实上这是
In fact, this is Nigel
奈吉尔从同一辆黑色SUV中走出来
stepping out of the very same black S.U.V.
我觉得不是
No, I don't think so.
你还是仔细看看吧
Why don't you take a closer look?
门上有着一样的定制条纹
It's got the same custom pinstripes on the door.
肯定是别人的车  条纹一样罢了
It's just somebody else's truck with those stripes on there.
你的司机已经承认开车
Your driver already admitted that he drove you
送你去领事馆碰面
to this meeting outside the consulate.
我们也知道你的表弟在服役
We also know that your cousin is in the service--
德鲁·哈里斯
Drew Harris.
参谋军士  他在军械库任职
A staff sergeant. He works at an armory.
他提供了那些导弹
He supplied the missiles.
你知道温德姆能
You knew that Wyndham had access
搞到外交包裹  你看到了机会
to the diplomatic pouch, and you saw an opportunity.
供需关系
Supply and demand.
老兄  你们这都是臆测
That's a whole lot of speculation there, mate.
不止我们发现了这件事
Well, we weren't the only ones to put together the pieces.
娜奥米没有给你她的电话号码
Naomi wasn't giving you her phone number.
她在找证据
She was looking for evidence.
当你意识到她就是被温德姆发现
Once you realized that she was the same girl
四处查探的女孩
that Wyndham caught snooping,
你跟踪她  并在旅馆杀了她
You followed her to the motel and you killed her.
你们怎么证明呢
Well, how y'all gon' prove that?
娜奥米身上有部分指纹
A partial fingerprint on Naomi's body--
跟你的刚好匹配
and it's a match to you.
有件事
You know, the thing
我搞不懂  为什么是乌干达
that I still can't figure out is, why uganda?
你为什么要在乎
Why would you care?
跟乌干达没关系
Man, it wasn't about Uganda.
就是为了钱
It was just about the money.
我都不知道温德姆把货送到哪里
I didn't even know where Wyndham was shipping the stuff to.
好的  打给我的助理
Good. Uh, call my assistant.
我一周都有时间
I am, uh, wide open all week.
事实上你没有
Actually, you're not.
下周也没有
Or the following week, for that matter.
告诉过你我们会再见面的
Told you I'd see you soon.
这是干什么
What is this?
被人赶出去一次
Getting thrown out of here once already
还觉得不够吗
wasn't enough for you people?
保安
Security.
他们帮不了你  没人能帮你
They can't help you, mate. Nobody can.
你那富有的乌干达朋友也帮不了
Not even your well-funded Ugandan friends.
奈吉尔·温德姆
Nigel Wyndham...
你因在国际走私军火及共谋杀死一名
You're under arrest for international arms trafficking
英国公民而被捕
and for abetting in the murder of a british citizen.
他爸爸会很自豪的
Her dad would've been proud...
她那么勇敢  对抗这些人
How brave she was, taking on these men.
但我真希望她没有这样做
But I so wish she hadn't done it.
你会去哪儿  华盛顿吗
So what happens now? Do you go back to D.C.?
回伦敦
London, I'm afraid.
接受应得的惩罚
Face the music.
他们应该嘉奖你的
You know, they should give you a commendation.
那是各种不可能的
Well, that is wildly improbable.
贝克特探长
Well, Detective Beckett,
很荣幸与你共事
it's been a true pleasure.
是我很荣幸  亨特警部
The pleasure was all mine, Detective Inspector Hunt.
请叫我科林
Please. Colin.
凯特
Kate.
我上飞机前还有几个小时时间
You know, I have a few hours before my flight, Kate.
你能赏脸跟我喝一杯吗
Could I persuade you to let me buy you a drink?
抱歉  有材料要写
I'm sorry. I have a bit of paperwork to do.
改天吧
Another time.
苏格兰场小子去哪儿了
Where's Scotland Yard off to?
回伦敦了
Oh, he's going back to london.
卡塞尔  你有时间吗
Castle, do you have a second?
我们能谈...
Can we talk--
没时间  贾辛达把法拉利
Actually, I don't. Jacinda has the Ferrari
违章停在了卸货区
double parked in a loading zone.
三天四次约会  你喜欢她
Four dates in three days. You like her.
是啊  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
她不像你喜欢的类型
Uh, she just--she doesn't seem like your type.
她风趣而简单
Well, she's fun and uncomplicated.
正是我现在所需要的
I think that's what my life needs right now.
嗨  我是凯特
Hi. It's, uh, it's kate.
还想请我喝一杯吗
Do you still want to buy me that drink?